Guide to the University of Chicago Department of Botany Records 1882-1972
University of Chicago Library
- Series VI: Photographs, circa 1891-1936
  - Subseries 7: Lantern Slides
    - Indiana, AEP-INS1, Cornus florida, Bailly Town, Indiana AEP-INS10, Slough 8, a view of beach ridges and sloughs in a very dry season, Buffington, Indiana AEP-INS12, Spring aspect at Slough 14, with a view of beach ridges and sloughs, between Buffington and Pine, Indiana AEP-INS13, Early spring at Slough 58, Buffington, Indiana AEP-INS14, A beach formed by ice, Cedar lake, Indiana AEP-INS19, Carya illinoinensis, Decker, Indiana AEP-INS20, A single Carya laciniosa in summer condition, Decker, Indiana AEP-INS21, Carya laciniosa in a floodplain forest, Decker, Indiana AEP-INS24, Witches Broom on a single Celtis occidentalis, Decker, Indiana AEP-INS25, The trunk of a Liquidambar styraciflua, Decker, Indiana AEP-INS26, A single Platanus occidentalis in spring, Decker, Indiana AEP-INS27, A single Taxodium distichum on upland, Decker, Indiana AEP-INS28, A Taxodium distichum forest and swamp, Decker, Indiana AEP-INS29, A distant view of a Taxodium distichum forest and swamp, Decker, Indiana AEP-INS30, A Taxodium distichum forest and swamp, Decker, Indiana AEP-INS31, Red Maple standing between Cypress knees, Decker, Indiana AEP-INS32, Taxodium distichum sprouting from a cut stump, Decker, Indiana AEP-INS33, The trunk of a Taxodium distichum showing a burl, Decker, Indiana AEP-INS36, Members of the International Phytogeographic Excursion in America, on the dunes, Miller, Indiana AEP-INS38, An advance of dunes near the Crater, Dune Park, Indiana AEP-INS60, Arctostaphylos uva-ursi at the dunes, Dune Park, Indiana AEP-INS61, A close view of two Gentiana andrewsii, Dune Park, Indiana AEP-INS62, A close view of three Geastrum sp. on the sand, Dune Park, Indiana AEP-INS63, A detail of a flowering clump of Euphorbia corollata in a dune habitat, Dune Park, Indiana AEP-INS64, A close view of Rudbeckia hirta, Dune Park, Indiana AEP-INS65, A close view of flowering Solidago sp. on a dune, Dune Park, Indiana AEP-INS67, Tephrosia virginiana, Dune Park, Indiana AEP-INS68, Salix humilis, Dune Park, Indiana AEP-INS69, A close view of flowering Solidago sp. on a dune, Dune Park, Indiana AEP-INS70, Pine on a rippled windward slope, Dune Park, Indiana AEP-INS74, Advancing dunes, Dune Park, Indiana AEP-INS75, The advance of dunes near the Crater, Dune Park, Indiana AEP-INS76, The soil line of the Crater, Dune Park, Indiana AEP-INS77, The Crater exposing its former soil line, Dune Park, Indiana AEP-INS80, Populus deltoides, Dune Park, Indiana AEP-INS81, An advance of dunes, Dune Park, Indiana AEP-INS82, Cornus stolonifera on an advancing dune, Furnessville, Indiana AEP-INS83, The beach at Dune Park, Indiana AEP-INS84, The spring aspect of an advancing dune, Furnessville, Indiana AEP-INS85, Buried snowdrift dunes at the camp of naturalist Elliot Rowland Downing, Indiana AEP-INS86, Snow on an ice slope, Indiana AEP-INS87, Advancing dune in an area denuded by steam shoveling, Dune Park, Indiana AEP-INS88, Vitis on dead trees which surround a moving dune, Furnessville, Indiana AEP-INS89, Ice on the Lake Michigan shore, Dune Park, Indiana AEP-INS90, A sand bar in Lake Michigan offshore from Dune Park, Indiana AEP-INS91, Buried snowdrift dunes in spring, Indiana AEP-INS92, Roots of a lone Populus deltoides, Dune Park, Indiana AEP-INS93, A lone Cottonwood, Dune Park, Indiana AEP-INS94, The removal of the dunes, Dune Park, Indiana AEP-INS95, Uncovering a buried Tilia americana, Dune Park, Indiana AEP-INS96, A lone Cottonwood in spring, Dune Park, Indiana AEP-INS97, A lone Cottonwood, Dune Park, Indiana AEP-INS98, A close view of a fallen Cottonwood, Dune Park, Indiana AEP-INS99, The exposed stem roots of an uncovered Populus deltoides, Dune Park, Indiana AEP-INS100, Tilia americana, a reference tree of dune advance with adventitious roots, Dune Park, Indiana AEP-INS101, Tilia americana, a reference tree of dune advance with adventitious roots, Dune Park, Indiana AEP-INS102, Tilia americana buried by a dune, Indiana AEP-INS104, A Pinus strobus graveyard, Furnessville, Indiana AEP-INS105, The encroachment of a dune upon a Bulrush and Water Lily swamp, Dune Park, Indiana AEP-INS111, The trunk of a Betula lutea, Mineral Springs, Indiana AEP-INS112, A close view of two flowering Calopogon pulchellus, Mineral Springs, Indiana AEP-INS114, Calopogon pulchellus in a bog, Mineral Springs, Indiana AEP-INS115, A trunk study of a Carya glabra, Mineral Springs, Indiana AEP-INS116, Carya glabra habitat, Mineral Springs, Indiana AEP-INS117, A close view of flowering Cornus canadensis, Mineral Springs, Indiana AEP-INS118, A clump of flowering Cypripedium hirsutum, Mineral Springs, Indiana AEP-INS119, Overturned Larix showing shallow roots, Mineral Springs, Indiana AEP-INS120, Larix laricina bog, Mineral Springs, Indiana AEP-INS121, Quercus velutina and seedling and Larix laricina in a bog, Mineral Springs, Indiana AEP-INS122, A close view of a flowering Mitchella repens, Mineral Springs, Indiana AEP-INS123, Nyssa sylvatica trunk, Mineral Springs, Indiana AEP-INS125, A flowering clump of Phlox pilosa, Mineral Springs, Indiana AEP-INS126, Pinus strobus, Mineral Springs, Indiana AEP-INS128, Sassafras variifolium in winter, Mineral Springs, Indiana AEP-INS129, A close view of flowering Trientalis americana, Mineral Springs, Indiana AEP-INS130, Woodwardia virginiana in a bog, Mineral Springs, Indiana AEP-INS131, A road in winter, Mineral Springs, Indiana AEP-INS132, Nyssa sylvatica, Furnessville, Indiana AEP-INS133, Panax trifolius growing in an area between Furnessville and Otis, Indiana AEP-INS137, The now destroyed Beach Ridge 2 with Pinus banksiana, west of Gary, Indiana AEP-INS139, A group of Juniperus virginiana, Keiser, Indiana AEP-INS140, Ice barriers formed off of a beach, Long Lake, Indiana AEP-INS141, Ice barriers formed off of a beach, Long Lake, Indiana AEP-INS143, Pinus strobus and Tilia glabra on an eroding dune shoreline, Michigan City, Indiana AEP-INS148, A large and thick clump of Prunus virginiana on an eroding dune, Miller, Indiana AEP-INS153, Carya glabra in summer, Mill Creek, Indiana AEP-INS154, Sassafras variifolium in summer, Mill Creek, Indiana AEP-INS163, A close view of a single Lobelia, Miller, Indiana AEP-INS165, A close view showing the flowers and leaves of Castalia tuberosa, Miller, Indiana AEP-INS166, Asclepias tuberosa, Miller, Indiana AEP-INS167, A single Sagittaria latifolia in its environment showing flowers and fruit, Miller, Indiana AEP-INS169, A lagoon with Castalia and Scirpus validus, Miller, Indiana AEP-INS170, A lagoon with Castalia and Scirpus validus, Miller, Indiana AEP-INS171, A clump of European Barberry before removal by a team and log chain, De Kalb County, Indiana AEP-INS174, Calamovilfa longifolia, Miller, Indiana AEP-INS175, Quercus velutina and Quercus alba on dunes, Miller, Indiana AEP-INS176, The interior of a Quercus velutina dune forest at Station 6, Miller, Indiana AEP-INS177, The exterior of a Quercus velutina dune forest, Miller, Indiana AEP-INS178, Pinus banksiana on the crest of a dune, Miller, Indiana AEP-INS179, Populus deltoides seedling, Miller, Indiana AEP-INS180, Cottonwood and Pine pocket and a dune advancing into the Grand Calumet River at Lake Street, Miller, Indiana AEP-INS181, Panne with Cottonwood seedling, Miller, Indiana AEP-INS182, A panne with Cottonwood seedling, Miller, Indiana AEP-INS183, A panne with Cottonwood seedling, Miller, Indiana AEP-INS184, A sand bar and lagoon on a depositing shore, Miller, Indiana AEP-INS185, University of Chicago Botany student Mandayam Sampathkumaran in snow on the dunes, Miller, Indiana AEP-INS186, A dune advancing into the Grand Calumet River at Lake Street, Miller, Indiana AEP-INS187, A dune advancing into the Grand Calumet River at Lake Street, Miller, Indiana AEP-INS188, A dune advancing into the Grand Calumet River, Miller, Indiana AEP-INS189, A dune advancing into the Grand Calumet River east of the bridge at Lake Street, Miller, Indiana AEP-INS201, A fallen log with saprophytic fungi, Otis, Indiana AEP-INS202, Fleshy fungus on a Beech, Otis Indiana AEP-INS203, Liriodendron tulipifera, Otis, Indiana AEP-INS204, Orchis spectabilis, Otis Indiana AEP-INS205, The trunk of an Ostrya virginiana, Otis, Indiana AEP-INS206, The trunk of a Prunus serotina, Otis, Indiana AEP-INS208, The trunk of a Quercus alba, Otis, Indiana AEP-INS209, A single Sambucus racemosa, Otis Indiana AEP-INS210, Tilia americana, Otis, Indiana AEP-INS211, Xerophytic stages of ravines, Otis, Indiana AEP-INS212, Gully erosion in Valparaiso moraine formerly a Beech and Maple forest, Otis, Indiana AEP-INS213, A ravine in a Beech and Maple forest in Valparaiso moraine, Otis Indiana AEP-INS214, The remains of Acer rubrum, Platanus, and Liriodendron, Perry County, Indiana AEP-INS215, Acer rubrum in an artificial lake caused by silting at the mouth of a stream, Perry County, Indiana AEP-INS216, A view looking toward a dam of Carya beside a lagoon, Perry County, Indiana AEP-INS217, Fagus and Carya on the edge of a lagoon formed by stream migration, Perry County, Indiana AEP-INS218, Remnants of a Beech forest, Perry County, Indiana AEP-INS219, Young Beech trees in the foreground, Perry County, Indiana AEP-INS220, Beech maintaining itself on an eroding slope, Perry County, Indiana AEP-INS221, The trunk of a thirty year old Liriodendron tulipifera, Perry County, Indiana AEP-INS222, Liriodendron tulipifera and Juniperus virginiana coming in over an old Fagus, Acer, and Juglans forest, Perry County, Indiana AEP-INS223, Nyssa aquatica still alive in a lagoon, Perry County, Indiana AEP-INS224, Stumps of Platanus and Juglans cinerea in a lagoon, Perry County, Indiana AEP-INS225, A lagoon edge, Perry County, Indiana AEP-INS226, A lagoon, Perry County, Indiana AEP-INS227, The "Old Swimming Hole" twenty-four years after, Perry County, Indiana AEP-INS228, The "Old Swimming Hole" twenty-four years after, Perry County, Indiana AEP-INS229, Water effects, Perry County, Indiana AEP-INS230, Water effects, Perry County, Indiana AEP-INS235, Pond 1 in early spring, Pine, Indiana AEP-INS236, Jack Pine and a small Sedge pool at Beach Ridge 4, Pine, Indiana AEP-INS237, Slough 90 looking east from the Elgin, Joliet, and Eastern railroad tracks, Pine Indiana AEP-INS238, Marsh Marigold and Skunk Cabbage, Portchester, Indiana AEP-INS239, A close view of Caltha palustris with Podophyllum peltatum, Portchester, Indiana AEP-INS240, A relict clump of Tilia americana, Portchester, Indiana AEP-INS241, A new moving dune, Portchester, Indiana AEP-INS242, Dunes near Lake Michigan, Indiana AEP-INS243, Scirpus, Sagittaria, and Typha in a ponded portion of the Whitewater River, Richmond, Indiana AEP-INS244, Sagittaria and Typha, Richmond, Indiana AEP-INS245, Exposure of Cincinnati limestone and shale, Richmond, Indiana AEP-INS246, Interior of a Fagus grandifolia forest, Rome, Indiana AEP-INS247, The interior of a Fagus grandifolia forest, Rome, Indiana AEP-INS248, Phoradendron on an Ulmus branch, Rome, Indiana AEP-INS251, Cephalanthus occidentalis, Salix nigra, and Typha in a kettle swamp, Smith, Indiana AEP-INS252, Close view of flowering Trillium grandiflorum, Smith Indiana AEP-INS253, An Ulmus americana with excrescences on its trunk, Smith Indiana AEP-INS254, Andropogon scoparius, Tremont, Indiana AEP-INS255, Pinus banksiana fruit, Tremont, Indiana AEP-INS256, Quercus velutina fruit, Tremont, Indiana AEP-INS263, A burl on a Quercus rubra, Indiana AEP-INS264, Henry Chandler Cowles of the University of Chicago Department of Botany and Sir Arthur George Tansley of Cambridge University on the dunes, Indiana AEP-INS265, Henry Chandler Cowles of the University of Chicago Department of Botany and Sir Arthur George Tansley of Cambridge University on the dunes, Indiana AEP-INS266, The leeward side of an advancing dune in summer, Indiana (Box CABINET 1, Folder Drawers 16-18)
    - Iowa, AEP-IAS1, Morus rubra, Davenport, Iowa AEP-IAS2, A levee, Suburban Island, Davenport, Iowa AEP-IAS3, River steamers on the Mississippi River, Davenport, Iowa AEP-IAS4, Mississippi bluffs and floodplain, Fairport, Iowa AEP-IAS5, The Mississippi River from Wyoming Hill, Fairport, Iowa AEP-IAS6, The Keokuk Power Plant showing 15 generators, Keokuk, Iowa AEP-IAS7, The Keokuk Dam, Keokuk, Iowa AEP-IAS8, A drowned valley caused by the Keokuk Dam, Iowa AEP-IAS9, A United States Fisheries Laboratory, Fairport, Iowa AEP-IAS10, The Mississippi River at Muscatine, Iowa AEP-IAS11, Nelumbo lutea, McGregor, Iowa (Box CABINET 1, Folder Drawer 18)
    - Kentucky, AEP-KYS1, A Quercus forest on the summit of Pine Mountain Range at the border of Bell and Whitley Counties, Kentucky AEP-KYS2, Acer saccharum and Aesculus glabra with a rich herbaceous layer, the slopes of Black Mountain, Letcher County, Kentucky AEP-KYS3, Acer saccharum on the higher slopes of Black Mountain, Letcher County, Kentucky AEP-KYS4, A Quercus forest on a ridge and slope with an understage of Cornus florida, Letcher County, Kentucky AEP-KYS5, Mixed mesophytic forest slopes of Black Mountain at the drainage basin of Joe Day Branch, Letcher County, Kentucky AEP-KYS6, Pine Mountain Range summit, a view of the north slope and Line Fork with a dead Castanea dentata, Letcher County, Kentucky AEP-KYS7, One thousand feet to the summit of Pine Mountain Range, a view above Line Fork of Tilia sp., Letcher County, Kentucky AEP-KYS8, A mixed forest of Quercus on lower slopes and Cornus florida, Lewis County, Kentucky AEP-KYS9, Mistletoe on Locust, Stephensport, Kentucky (Box CABINET 1, Folder Drawer 18)
    - Louisiana, AEP-LAS1, A levee near Bordelonville, Louisiana breached by the Mississippi River flood of 1927 AEP-LAS2, First and second terraces at Ferry Lake, Louisiana AEP-LAS3, Some victims of the 1927 Mississippi River flood gathered at Hamburg, Louisiana AEP-LAS4, Pinus palustris viewed on a field trip from New Orleans, Louisiana AEP-LAS5, Pine woods on upland, Shreveport, Louisiana AEP-LAS6, A forest of Pinus taeda, Louisiana AEP-LAS7, Forest of Pinus taeda, Louisiana AEP-LAS8, Quercus alba in a mesophytic forest, Louisiana AEP-LAS9, Taxodium distichum, Louisiana AEP-LAS10, Erosion of an environmentally devastated plain, Louisiana (Box CABINET 1, Folder Drawer 18)
    - Maryland, AEP-MDS1, A lumbering town, Krug, Maryland AEP-MDS2, Sawing trees into logs, Krug, Maryland AEP-MDS3, Snaking logs, Krug, Maryland AEP-MDS4, Loading logs, Krug, Maryland AEP-MDS5, Unloading logs at the mill, Krug, Maryland AEP-MDS6, The sawmill in Krug, Maryland (Box CABINET 1, Folder Drawer 18)
    - Maine, AEP-MES4, An upland Beech and Maple forest, Maine AEP-MES5, Close view of Betula papyrifera, northern Maine AEP-MES6, Betula lenta trunk, Maine AEP-MES7, The lichen Usnea ciliata, Maine AEP-MES8, The lichen Usnea ciliata, Maine AEP-MES9, The interior of a forest with Picea canadensis, Maine AEP-MES10, Picea reproducing under Populus, northern Maine AEP-MES11, Impatiens balsamina under Betula papyrifera, northern Maine AEP-MES12, A forest of Picea, northern Maine AEP-MES13, Pinus resinosa, northern Maine (Box CABINET 1, Folder Drawer 18)